<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">
    <title>Chip Blogs Things</title>
    <link href="https://blog.chipjohnson.net/feed.xml" rel="self" />
    <link href="https://blog.chipjohnson.net" />
    <updated>2023-01-01T19:13:33-08:00</updated>
    <author>
        <name>Chip Johnson</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://blog.chipjohnson.net</id>

    <entry>
        <title>When the Lights Go Out</title>
        <author>
            <name>Chip Johnson</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://blog.chipjohnson.net/when-the-lights-go-out.html"/>
        <id>https://blog.chipjohnson.net/when-the-lights-go-out.html</id>
        <media:content url="https://blog.chipjohnson.net/media/posts/4/IMG_8245-2.PNG" medium="image" />
            <category term="Twitter"/>
            <category term="DevOps"/>
            <category term="Cloud"/>

        <updated>2023-01-01T19:13:33-08:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://blog.chipjohnson.net/media/posts/4/IMG_8245-2.PNG" alt="" />
                    Say what you will about Twitter and its impact on our culture, but you can't deny that the people building it acted with passion and care. Since the end of October, when the company was bought out and taken private, those creators have watched helplessly&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <p><img src="https://blog.chipjohnson.net/media/posts/4/IMG_8245-2.PNG" class="type:primaryImage" alt="" /></p>
                
  <p>
    Say what you will about Twitter and its impact on our culture, but you can't deny that the people building it acted with passion and care. Since the end of October, when the company was bought out and taken private, those creators have watched helplessly as the new owners transformed the company and the project born of their dedication into something else entirely.<br>
  </p>

  <p>
    Before the change in management, many people working at Twitter had been wary of what the company's famously capricious billionaire suitor might do. But the reality turned out to be far crueler than they'd imagined, and conversations lamenting the destruction from current and former Twitter employees have dominated tech social media.<br>
  </p>

  <p>
    For many of them, this was their first Lights Out moment.&nbsp;<br>
  </p>

  <p>
    Lights Out moments are a new phenomenon brought on by the internet age. Throughout history, most people have supported themselves by expressing ideas, creating and enforcing agreements with other humans,  or building and arranging tangible objects—things made of atoms. However, for those working on the internet, we can now make money by arranging electrons. And it turns out that specific configurations of electrons are extremely rewarding, and some are even extremely profitable!<br>
  </p>

  <p>
    But by their very nature, a pleasing configuration of electrons is a fleeting thing. As all of these Twitter employees are discovering, when you're an electron worker, all someone has to do to permanently erase your life's work is turn off the power. Lights Out.<br>
  </p>

  <p>
    This is not to say that it is rare or unusual for a person to see all of their efforts destroyed capriciously. But the incredible ease with which any number of phenomena can wipe them out is a new phenomenon of the electron worker. It is a bitter but necessary lesson for anyone who wants to be in tech, and I was lucky to learn it early in my career.
  </p>

    <figure class="post__image post__image--center">
      <img loading="lazy" src="https://blog.chipjohnson.net/media/posts/4/golden-storage-production.s3.amazonaws.com-topic_images-b62f03d34f164739b6b26de2d82d854c.png" height="200" width="200" alt="amp'd"  sizes="100vw" srcset="https://blog.chipjohnson.net/media/posts/4/responsive/golden-storage-production.s3.amazonaws.com-topic_images-b62f03d34f164739b6b26de2d82d854c-xs.webp 300w ,https://blog.chipjohnson.net/media/posts/4/responsive/golden-storage-production.s3.amazonaws.com-topic_images-b62f03d34f164739b6b26de2d82d854c-sm.webp 480w ,https://blog.chipjohnson.net/media/posts/4/responsive/golden-storage-production.s3.amazonaws.com-topic_images-b62f03d34f164739b6b26de2d82d854c-md.webp 768w ,https://blog.chipjohnson.net/media/posts/4/responsive/golden-storage-production.s3.amazonaws.com-topic_images-b62f03d34f164739b6b26de2d82d854c-lg.webp 1024w ,https://blog.chipjohnson.net/media/posts/4/responsive/golden-storage-production.s3.amazonaws.com-topic_images-b62f03d34f164739b6b26de2d82d854c-xl.webp 1360w ,https://blog.chipjohnson.net/media/posts/4/responsive/golden-storage-production.s3.amazonaws.com-topic_images-b62f03d34f164739b6b26de2d82d854c-2xl.webp 1600w">
      <figcaption>Amp'd Mobile Logo</figcaption>
    </figure>

  <p>
    In 2005, I helped launch a cell phone company with a revolutionary idea: They had an app store that sold movies, TV shows, music, games, and communication tools, all from the handset. It seems passé now, but before iPhones, the concept was incredibly innovative. Unfortunately, they also tried to do it from clunky Kyocera slider phones.&nbsp;Amp'd couldn't even offer customers a Motorola RAZR for their first year in business.
  </p>
<div><div class="post__iframe"><iframe loading="lazy" width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/4yuiIew6Lfs" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen></iframe></div></div>

  <p>
    To say it didn't work out is an understatement. AMP'd Mobile burned through $350M of investor cash in less than two years, arguably the last significant failure of the first .com era.
  </p>

  <p>
    As the lead systems admin on their infrastructure, I routinely put in 80-hour weeks with 24/7 on-call. I spent days sleeping on cots in warehouse data centers and eating fast food in the conference room, never seeing the sun while we racked giant SAN clusters and live-migrated data. I wrote new tooling to solve problems nobody else had ever solved before, putting the best of my creativity and life into the project. Get me in the right mood, and I might tell you the story about being wrecked out of my mind at a New Year's Eve party with a half-dozen other sysadmin friends, all of us slurring into a speakerphone at a poor NOC technician about how to kill and safely restart a desynched JBoss cluster.
  </p>

  <p>
    I was young, I was at the top of my game, and I gave Amp'd everything I had.
  </p>

  <p>
    One day, they stopped paying their bills, so we just... turned the servers off and never turned them back on. All of the best work of my young career went away with a shutdown command.
  </p>

    <figure class="post__image post__image--center">
      <img loading="lazy" src="https://blog.chipjohnson.net/media/posts/4/linux-shutdown.png" height="307" width="713" alt=""  sizes="100vw" srcset="https://blog.chipjohnson.net/media/posts/4/responsive/linux-shutdown-xs.webp 300w ,https://blog.chipjohnson.net/media/posts/4/responsive/linux-shutdown-sm.webp 480w ,https://blog.chipjohnson.net/media/posts/4/responsive/linux-shutdown-md.webp 768w ,https://blog.chipjohnson.net/media/posts/4/responsive/linux-shutdown-lg.webp 1024w ,https://blog.chipjohnson.net/media/posts/4/responsive/linux-shutdown-xl.webp 1360w ,https://blog.chipjohnson.net/media/posts/4/responsive/linux-shutdown-2xl.webp 1600w">
      
    </figure>

  <p>
    I had something of an existential crisis. Seeing how fragile and fleeting my best efforts were, what were they genuinely worth, in the end? It was incredibly humbling. Did I even want to do this kind of work anymore? How much of myself could I continue to put into my career?
  </p>

  <p>
    What did I want the impact of my life to be?
  </p>

  <p>
    In the fifteen years since Amp'd Mobile folded up, I've been part of a few more Lights Out events and have watched others experience them for the first time. I've tried to be there for dozens of my colleagues and friends as they've wrestled with these same questions. It hasn't been easy for anyone; some have become quite bitter.
  </p>

  <p>
    I imagine these same questions are what the Twitter alums are dealing with right now. It will be difficult for them, too. But this is a necessary step in the career for anyone who wants to arrange electrons for a living. Because the things we make, the ways we express our creativity, none of it is tangible. It can all go away with the press of a button. And we have to face that part of the bargain with our eyes open. Making something lasting of our lives is difficult, and very few of us will ever do it. But making something lasting with electrons? It might be damn near impossible.
  </p>

    <figure class="post__image post__image--center">
      <img loading="lazy" src="https://blog.chipjohnson.net/media/posts/4/im-669602.jpeg" height="1280" width="1280" alt="Twitter headstone"  sizes="100vw" srcset="https://blog.chipjohnson.net/media/posts/4/responsive/im-669602-xs.webp 300w ,https://blog.chipjohnson.net/media/posts/4/responsive/im-669602-sm.webp 480w ,https://blog.chipjohnson.net/media/posts/4/responsive/im-669602-md.webp 768w ,https://blog.chipjohnson.net/media/posts/4/responsive/im-669602-lg.webp 1024w ,https://blog.chipjohnson.net/media/posts/4/responsive/im-669602-xl.webp 1360w ,https://blog.chipjohnson.net/media/posts/4/responsive/im-669602-2xl.webp 1600w">
      <figcaption>Twitter headstone</figcaption>
    </figure>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>An Obvious Thing About the Cloud</title>
        <author>
            <name>Chip Johnson</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://blog.chipjohnson.net/an-obvious-thing-about-the-cloud.html"/>
        <id>https://blog.chipjohnson.net/an-obvious-thing-about-the-cloud.html</id>
        <media:content url="https://blog.chipjohnson.net/media/posts/3/A772A922-B765-4B5D-AC88-CB46C4A215CA_1_105_c.jpeg" medium="image" />
            <category term="DevOps"/>
            <category term="Cloud"/>
            <category term="AWS"/>

        <updated>2022-11-10T11:13:20-08:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://blog.chipjohnson.net/media/posts/3/A772A922-B765-4B5D-AC88-CB46C4A215CA_1_105_c.jpeg" alt="Abandoned computer equipment" />
                    (This post started life as a Twitter thread.) There's a blog post by DHH that's getting lots of traction lately about how his company, 37signals, is abandoning the cloud. Because he's DHH, this becomes a long rant about self-reliance and cutting out predatory middlemen. He&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <p><img src="https://blog.chipjohnson.net/media/posts/3/A772A922-B765-4B5D-AC88-CB46C4A215CA_1_105_c.jpeg" class="type:primaryImage" alt="Abandoned computer equipment" /></p>
                
  <p class="msg msg--info">
    <i>(This post started life as a <a href="https://twitter.com/JefrsonStarChip/status/1583220749594071040?s=20&amp;t=v3KaY_evH0bkAp-6LugbVw">Twitter thread</a>.)</i>
  </p>

  <p>
    There's a blog post by DHH that's getting lots of traction lately about how his company, 37signals, is abandoning the cloud. Because he's DHH, this becomes a long rant about self-reliance and cutting out predatory middlemen. He says some things that seem so stunningly obvious to me they're not worth talking about, but he managed to get 1,000 words, countless page views, and a 30-minute podcast out of it, so hey! I guess maybe it is worth talking about!
  </p>

  <p>
    Here's your tl;dr: The folks at 37signals have predictable workloads and a lot of in-house expertise around running servers &amp; networks in a data center. So they ran the numbers and figured out they'd save a lot of money by moving all of their applications out of the cloud and onto self-managed infrastructure.&nbsp;
  </p>

  <p>
    That's it. That's the tweet. But DHH presents this as a stunning revelation when in reality, it's... Yeah? No shit? You can use excel; congratulations. If I knew this silly little thought would blow minds, I'd have been saying it louder through the years.
  </p>

  <p>
    <b>It should be obvious, but if you have predictable workloads and in-house infrastructure expertise, you will probably save money running your own infrastructure instead of using AWS.</b><br><br>Look, cloud hosting <i>can</i> run mature, low-maintenance apps for you. But that's not what it's for. The cloud was designed for rapid time-to-market. And it works! Now, if you want to create a wholly new experience on the internet, you can go home and get that idea in front of people before you go to sleep tonight. That's incredible.
  </p>

  <p>
    The barriers to creating a thing on the internet used to be enormous and expensive until the cloud tore those obstacles down. As a result, the number of people running workloads on the internet is many, many times greater than it was when, as DDH put it, "Everyone &amp; their dog [ran infrastructure] to get the internet off the ground."
  </p>

  <p>
    <i>My dog &amp; I also waited six months for Rackspace.com to provision new servers, my dude. </i>People today don't have that problem. They put in a credit card number and have all the computing power they need, billed by the hour.
  </p>

    <figure class="blockquote">
      <blockquote>The world doesn't need thousands of people who can expertly tune postfix, SpamAssassin, and ClamAV—the world has Gmail.</blockquote>
      <figcaption>Charity Majors</figcaption>
    </figure>

  <p>
    In a recent article, Charity Majors <a href="https://www.honeycomb.io/blog/future-ops-platform-engineering" target="_blank">wrote about the bifurcation of infrastructure engineering and operations engineering</a>. Infrastructure engineering is commoditizing because every company needs it, and no company can differentiate on it. On the other hand, operations engineering is getting a new name because we're technologists,&nbsp;<i style="font-weight: bold;">that's what we do here,</i>&nbsp;and we seem to have settled on Platform Engineering. Because infrastructure commoditization makes sense, while platform engineering remains mostly bespoke, the tides of economic inevitability crashed. Someone figured out they could build a tollgated API between the roles as they decoupled, and we call that API the cloud.
  </p>

  <p>
    To put it another way: Running servers? As Jeff Barr says, that's <a href="https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/aws/we_build_muck_s/" target="_blank">undifferentiated heavy lifting</a>. But running my site and services? You bet your ass that my company runbook is a trade secret.
  </p>

  <p>
    <i>(A brief aside: Kubernetes is the foundation of the latest attempt to commodify operations expertise. It's going better than the last couple of dozen times people tried to do this, but it's still not there. A true Kubernetes expert currently costs about $500k/year, and they're worth every penny. So... not a commodity.)</i>
  </p>

  <p>
    What does this all mean? First, you can be a tech company without any infrastructure expertise. You can do it <i>in minutes</i> with just a credit card. You can ignore the infrastructure parts and put all your focus square on your customers. And it means that in those early days of pinching pennies and wild swings in requirements, when you might need a memory cache one day and a bunch of web servers the next, until you need to <b>stop paying for all of that ASAP </b>to try something else, you can adapt before you wind up dead.
  </p>

  <p>
    These are <i>superpowers.</i>&nbsp;It is <i>awesome</i>.&nbsp;DevOps isn't dead, it's alive and well, and you can buy it off the shelf.
  </p>

  <p>
    But once your product has matured, growth is steady, and you can make accurate predictions about your customer usage, all that flexibility stops meaning very much. And like most things rented by the hour, the cloud is expensive when you add it up to weeks, months, and years. So when you've got time to breathe and look around, you might find yourself a vast cloud bill. And if you've got the chops and some free time, well...
  </p>

  <p>
    I'm just going to say it again: <b>If you have predictable workloads and in-house infrastructure expertise, you will probably save money running your own infrastructure instead of using AWS.</b><br>
  </p>

  <p>
    What a dull, obvious sentence! I think it's boring, anyway. I got bored saying it to you. But leave it to a polemicist to turn a sensible business decision into a, uh, polemic:
  </p>

    <figure class="blockquote">
      <blockquote>Up until very recently, everyone ran their own servers, and much of the progress in tooling that enabled the cloud is available for your own machines as well. Don't let the entrenched cloud interests dazzle you into believing that running your own setup is too complicated...&nbsp;It's time to part the clouds and let the internet shine through.</blockquote>
      <figcaption>David Heinemeier Hansson (DHH)</figcaption>
    </figure>

  <p>
    Fuck right off with this attitude. If a product is no longer for you, don't buy it. But the cloud has done wonders to lower barriers to access and democratize the internet.
  </p>

  <p>
    Doing commoditized things in-house makes sense at some scales. But it's not a political act; it's an economic one. Don't let nostalgia for the days when you kept the dark magicks of <code>make installworld</code> for yourself convince you otherwise.
  </p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>November Election 2022</title>
        <author>
            <name>Chip Johnson</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://blog.chipjohnson.net/november-election-2022.html"/>
        <id>https://blog.chipjohnson.net/november-election-2022.html</id>
            <category term="Voter Guide"/>
            <category term="Harbor Bay Club"/>
            <category term="Alameda"/>

        <updated>2022-11-07T10:52:00-08:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    I'm going over my ballot for this November, and I thought writing a voter guide might be an excellent way to get my thoughts in order about the election. This post is 100% inspired by/blatantly aping David Glasser's awesome voter guides. I stole a lot&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p>I'm going over my ballot for this November, and I thought writing a voter guide might be an excellent way to get my thoughts in order about the election. This post is 100% inspired by/blatantly aping David Glasser's awesome voter guides. I stole a lot of his format.<br><br>I have to confess a certain amount of hopelessness about national politics. Republicans are maneuvering to take the vote away from anyone who isn't white while simultaneously pushing to make political gerrymandering legal and irreversible. If they have their way, this election might mark the end of the American experiment. Trumpism is flourishing! The former president's outright treason is going unpunished, while fascism and political violence are prevalent. I always used to scoff when people of my parent's generation told me Gen-X would fuck up the country! But here we are, and they were right.<br><br>Still, California will remain solidly progressive. Our federal representatives are going to be Democratic. The statehouse party supermajority is isn't threatened. That makes this election mostly about local races and ballot initiatives.</p>
<h1>Voter Guides I Used</h1>
<ul>
<li><a target="_blank" href="https://vote.davidglasser.net/post/202211/" class="editor-rtfLink" rel="noopener"></a><a href="https://vote.davidglasser.net/post/202211/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><span data-preserver-spaces="true">David Glasser</span></a><span data-preserver-spaces="true"> always posts an excellent, well-considered guide. I totally stole his "table of how I'm voting" section.</span></li>
<li><span data-preserver-spaces="true">I always check </span><a target="_blank" href="https://www.theleaguesf.org/Nov_2022#top" class="editor-rtfLink" rel="noopener"><span data-preserver-spaces="true">endorsements by the San Francisco League of Pissed-Off Voters</span></a><span data-preserver-spaces="true">.</span></li>
<li>The <a href="https://indivisiblesf.org/blog/2022/9/27/propositions-on-the-2022-octnov-ballot" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Indivisible SF endorsements</a> are worth checking out.</li>
<li>The <a href="https://www.cta.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/2022-Locally-Recommended-Candidates-Region-1_101422.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">California Teacher's Association endorsements</a></li>
<li><a href="https://laurendo.wordpress.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Lauren Do's blog</a> has many positions on Alameda-local races.</li>
<li>For statewide races, it's worth checking the <a target="_blank" href="https://www.sfchronicle.com/projects/2022/california-voter-guide-june/endorsements" class="editor-rtfLink" rel="noopener" style="font-family: var(--editor-font-family); font-size: inherit; font-weight: var(--font-weight-normal);"><span data-preserver-spaces="true">SF Chronicle Voter's Guide</span></a><span style="color: var(--text-primary-color); font-family: var(--editor-font-family); font-size: inherit; font-weight: var(--font-weight-normal);" data-preserver-spaces="true"> (this gets a lot less weight from me than many others)</span></li>
<li><span data-preserver-spaces="true">The </span><a target="_blank" href="https://cadem.org/endorsements/" class="editor-rtfLink" rel="noopener"><span data-preserver-spaces="true">California Democratic Party endorsements</span></a><span data-preserver-spaces="true"> (When in doubt...)</span></li>
<li>If I'm still undecided as an issue, I always check the <a href="https://www.cagop.org/s/endorsements">Califorrnia Republican Party endorsements</a>, then do the opposite.</li>
</ul>
<h1>How I'm Voting</h1>
<table style="border-collapse: collapse; width: 100%; height: 1921.03px;" border="1">
<thead>
<tr style="border-color: #000000; height: 50.3594px;">
<td style="width: 53.4991%; height: 50.3594px;"><strong>Race</strong></td>
<td style="width: 46.5009%; height: 50.3594px;"><strong>My Vote</strong></td>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr style="height: 50.3594px;">
<td style="width: 53.4991%; height: 50.3594px;">Governor</td>
<td style="width: 46.5009%; height: 50.3594px;">Gavin Newsom</td>
</tr>
<tr style="height: 50.3594px;">
<td style="width: 53.4991%; height: 50.3594px;">Lieutenant Governor</td>
<td style="width: 46.5009%; height: 50.3594px;">Eleni Kounalakis</td>
</tr>
<tr style="height: 50.3594px;">
<td style="width: 53.4991%; height: 50.3594px;">Secretary of State</td>
<td style="width: 46.5009%; height: 50.3594px;">Shirley Weber</td>
</tr>
<tr style="height: 50.3594px;">
<td style="width: 53.4991%; height: 50.3594px;">Controller</td>
<td style="width: 46.5009%; height: 50.3594px;">Malia Cohen</td>
</tr>
<tr style="height: 50.3594px;">
<td style="width: 53.4991%; height: 50.3594px;">Treasurer</td>
<td style="width: 46.5009%; height: 50.3594px;">Fiona Ma</td>
</tr>
<tr style="height: 50.3594px;">
<td style="width: 53.4991%; height: 50.3594px;">Attorney General</td>
<td style="width: 46.5009%; height: 50.3594px;">Rob Bonta</td>
</tr>
<tr style="height: 50.3594px;">
<td style="width: 53.4991%; height: 50.3594px;">Insurance Commissioner</td>
<td style="width: 46.5009%; height: 50.3594px;">Ricardo Lara</td>
</tr>
<tr style="height: 50.3594px;">
<td style="width: 53.4991%; height: 50.3594px;">State Board of Equalization, 2nd District</td>
<td style="width: 46.5009%; height: 50.3594px;">Sally Lieber</td>
</tr>
<tr style="height: 50.3594px;">
<td style="width: 53.4991%; height: 50.3594px;">United States Senate (Through 2023)</td>
<td style="width: 46.5009%; height: 50.3594px;">Alex Padilla</td>
</tr>
<tr style="height: 50.3594px;">
<td style="width: 53.4991%; height: 50.3594px;">United States Senate (Through 2029)</td>
<td style="width: 46.5009%; height: 50.3594px;">Alex Padilla</td>
</tr>
<tr style="height: 50.3594px;">
<td style="width: 53.4991%; height: 50.3594px;">12th Congressional District</td>
<td style="width: 46.5009%; height: 50.3594px;">Barbara Lee</td>
</tr>
<tr style="height: 50.3594px;">
<td style="width: 53.4991%; height: 50.3594px;">State Assembly 18th District</td>
<td style="width: 46.5009%; height: 50.3594px;">Mia Bonta</td>
</tr>
<tr style="height: 50.3594px;">
<td style="width: 53.4991%; height: 50.3594px;">Supreme Court Judges</td>
<td style="width: 46.5009%; height: 50.3594px;">Yes (All)</td>
</tr>
<tr style="height: 50.3594px;">
<td style="width: 53.4991%; height: 50.3594px;">Court of Appeals Judges</td>
<td style="width: 46.5009%; height: 50.3594px;">Yes (All)</td>
</tr>
<tr style="height: 50.3594px;">
<td style="width: 53.4991%; height: 50.3594px;">State Superintendent of Public Instruction</td>
<td style="width: 46.5009%; height: 50.3594px;">Tony Thurmond</td>
</tr>
<tr style="height: 79.1562px;">
<td style="width: 53.4991%; height: 79.1562px;">AUSD Governing Board</td>
<td style="width: 46.5009%; height: 79.1562px;">Ryan Lalonde<br>Gary Lim</td>
</tr>
<tr style="height: 50.3594px;">
<td style="width: 53.4991%; height: 50.3594px;">Alameda County Supervisor</td>
<td style="width: 46.5009%; height: 50.3594px;">Rebecca Kaplan</td>
</tr>
<tr style="height: 50.3594px;">
<td style="width: 53.4991%; height: 50.3594px;">Alameda County District Attorney</td>
<td style="width: 46.5009%; height: 50.3594px;">Pamela Price</td>
</tr>
<tr style="height: 50.3594px;">
<td style="width: 53.4991%; height: 50.3594px;">City of Alameda Mayor</td>
<td style="width: 46.5009%; height: 50.3594px;">Marilyn Ezzy Ashcraft</td>
</tr>
<tr style="height: 79.1562px;">
<td style="width: 53.4991%; height: 79.1562px;">City of Alameda City Council</td>
<td style="width: 46.5009%; height: 79.1562px;">Hannah Groce<br>Paul Beusterien</td>
</tr>
<tr style="height: 50.3594px;">
<td style="width: 53.4991%; height: 50.3594px;">AC Transit District Director At-Large</td>
<td style="width: 46.5009%; height: 50.3594px;">Alfred Twu</td>
</tr>
<tr style="height: 50.3594px;">
<td style="width: 53.4991%; height: 50.3594px;">AC Transit District Director, Ward 3</td>
<td style="width: 46.5009%; height: 50.3594px;">Sarah Syed</td>
</tr>
<tr style="height: 79.1562px;">
<td style="width: 53.4991%; height: 79.1562px;">Measure 1 (State constitutional right to abortion)</td>
<td style="width: 46.5009%; height: 79.1562px;">Hell yes</td>
</tr>
<tr style="height: 79.1562px;">
<td style="width: 53.4991%; height: 79.1562px;">Measure 26 (Expand gaming allowed on tribal lands)</td>
<td style="width: 46.5009%; height: 79.1562px;">Yes, I guess.</td>
</tr>
<tr style="height: 50.3594px;">
<td style="width: 53.4991%; height: 50.3594px;">Measure 27 (Allow online gambling)</td>
<td style="width: 46.5009%; height: 50.3594px;">No</td>
</tr>
<tr style="height: 79.1562px;">
<td style="width: 53.4991%; height: 79.1562px;">Measure 28 (New tax for arts in schools)</td>
<td style="width: 46.5009%; height: 79.1562px;">Yes</td>
</tr>
<tr style="height: 50.3594px;">
<td style="width: 53.4991%; height: 50.3594px;">Measure 29 (Kidney dialysis again)</td>
<td style="width: 46.5009%; height: 50.3594px;">Yes</td>
</tr>
<tr style="height: 79.1562px;">
<td style="width: 53.4991%; height: 79.1562px;">Measure 30 (Tax on $2M+ income to fund electric cars)</td>
<td style="width: 46.5009%; height: 79.1562px;">Yes</td>
</tr>
<tr style="height: 79.1562px;">
<td style="width: 53.4991%; height: 79.1562px;">Measure 31 (Keep law banning flavored tobacco)</td>
<td style="width: 46.5009%; height: 79.1562px;">Yes</td>
</tr>
<tr style="height: 79.1562px;">
<td style="width: 53.4991%; height: 79.1562px;">Alameda County D (More buildings on agricultural land)</td>
<td style="width: 46.5009%; height: 79.1562px;">Yes</td>
</tr>
<tr style="height: 79.1562px;">
<td style="width: 53.4991%; height: 79.1562px;">City of Alameda E (City council pay increases)</td>
<td style="width: 46.5009%; height: 79.1562px;">HELL YES</td>
</tr>
<tr style="height: 50.3594px;">
<td style="width: 53.4991%; height: 50.3594px;">City of Alameda F (Raise hotel taxes)</td>
<td style="width: 46.5009%; height: 50.3594px;">Yes</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<h1>Partisan Races</h1>
<p><strong><span data-preserver-spaces="true">Democrat down the ticket. </span></strong><span data-preserver-spaces="true">I've not consistently voted Democrat over my lifetime. But the modern Republican party has embraced fascism and political violence. Until they repudiate these stances, I never see myself voting for the party again.</span></p>
<p><span data-preserver-spaces="true">People are not their politics! I know many shithead progressives and Republicans that would give you the boots off their feet. I don't hold that all Republicans are bad people, but these days I do start from that assumption until they prove themselves otherwise.</span></p>
<h1>Judges</h1>
<p><strong>Yes to all. </strong>These are up-or-down votes about keeping judges in office. As David pointed out, the League of Pissed-Off Voters recommends voting yes on everybody. Honestly, that's good enough for me.</p>
<h1 id="state-superintendent-of-public-instruction-tony-thurmond">State Superintendent of Public Instruction</h1>
<p><strong>Thurmond. </strong>I'll quote David Glasser here:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>This one doesn’t say “Democrat vs Republican” on the ballot, but it is. Thurmond has apparently not been as great as hoped for in office. But Christensen is a Christian supremacist who wants to bring staff-led prayer to public schools. Vote Thurmond!</p>
</blockquote>
<h1 id="district-attorney-pamela-price">County Supervisor</h1>
<p><strong>Rebecca Kaplan. </strong>This is a tragic race. In a significant loss for the region, the incumbent, Wilma Chan, was struck and killed by a motorist about a year ago. She was an Alameda local and I met her a few times. By all accounts she was a good person and public servant.</p>
<p>The good news is that we have an embarrassment of riches in choosing her successor: Lena Tam was an excellent vice-mayor for Alameda, and I loved being her constituent. I've voted for her before; she'd do a good job. Kaplan was vice mayor of Oakland and is a single-issue candidate focused on homelessness. That's very attractive, and she's proposing innovative solutions. We won't go wrong either way.</p>
<h1 id="district-attorney-pamela-price">District Attorney</h1>
<p><strong>Pamela Price. </strong>David has written glowing recommendations for Pamela Price in the past. Pamela has the criminal reform endorsements, and Terry Wiley has the political machine endorsements. I don't think either will be a disaster, but David's considerable enthusiasm tilts me toward Pamela.</p>
<h1>AUSD Governing Board</h1>
<p><strong>Ryan Lalonde &amp; Gary Lim.</strong> </p>
<p><strong>Update: </strong>Ryan Lalonde reached out to me directly (validation endorphins!) with corrections. I was completely wrong!<strong> </strong>This is <em>totally</em> a maskers vs anti-maskers race, <em>and</em> one of the anti-maskers <a href="https://alamedapost.com/news/lwva-ausd-board-of-education-candidate-forum/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">told the league of Women Voters that she opposes LGBTQ curriculum</a>. Local blogger Lauren Do <a href="https://laurendo.wordpress.com/2022/10/13/pay-you-in-coupons/#more-34636" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">also had choice things to say about the race</a>.</p>
<p><span style="text-decoration: line-through;">I mainly want to ensure this wasn't one of those races where the Trumpists are trying to get some COVID-denier shithead onto the school board. Fortunately, that doesn't appear to be the case.</span></p>
<p><span style="text-decoration: line-through;">All the candidate information online is pretty milquetoast, so in the end, I went with the California Teacher's Association endorsements.</span></p>
<h1>AC Transit Races</h1>
<p><strong>Alfred Twu &amp; Sarah Syed. </strong>David has glowing recommendations for Alfred Twu, and Sarah Syed's credentials and experience are extremely impressive. These both seem like no-brainers.</p>
<h1>City of Alameda Mayor</h1>
<p><strong>Marilyn Ashcraft. </strong><strong>No on Trish. </strong>Marilyn Ashcraft has been an excellent mayor of Alameda. Between COVID and the state legislature entering into a "pro-growth-or-else" posture toward city governments, she's done a fantastic job.</p>
<p>Ashcraft brought us through the COVID emergency while minimizing the economic impact on local business. She has shepherded the city through creating a compliant California Housing Element, and the city transit plans designed under her leadership emphasize bicycles and pedestrians over cars. In addition, city council meetings once again run smoothly on her watch. It's been a harder time than usual to lead a city in California, and Marilyn Ashcraft has been a formidable wartime mayor.</p>
<p>On top of that, Ashcraft has been pro-tenant in a city where more than half of residents are renters. That's a big deal, even for homeowners like me.</p>
<p><span data-preserver-spaces="true">I love all of that, but in the end I'm a single-issue voter in Alameda city politics, and that issue is whether the owners of the Harbor Bay Club will be allowed to redevelop their site into housing. Earlier this year, </span><a target="_blank" href="https://alamedasun.com/news/development-company-applies-redevelop-harbor-bay-club-site" class="editor-rtfLink" rel="noopener"><span data-preserver-spaces="true">these jackasses proposed bulldozing the run-down tennis club next to my house and replacing it with an apartment tower featuring a 600-space parking garage. They wanted to build it about 60 feet from my home, with the parking garage entrance pointed directly at my front door</span></a><span data-preserver-spaces="true">. That proposal was ultimately defeated, but it's hardly the last attempt at redevelopment by the people who own the site. </span>Ashcraft hasn't precisely committed to opposing such a plan, but she's spoken in that direction:</p>
<blockquote class="">
<div class="">
<div class="gmail_quote">
<div class="" dir="ltr">
<div class="" dir="ltr">
<div class="">According to Planning, Building &amp; Transportation Director Andrew Thomas, "It is not an unreasonable request" to change the current zoning of the Harbor Bay Club (HBC) to make it consistent with the site's General Plan designation which is "Commercial Recreation" and would preclude housing. Mr. Thomas also noted significant concerns with the HBC site, including the need to address sea level rise. I have worked with Mr. Thomas since 2006 when I was appointed to the Planning Board and find his reasoning thorough and persuasive.</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</blockquote>
<p>That's not an "I would definitely oppose development there," but it's good enough for me.</p>
<p>All that said, I wasn't in love with how her government handled multiple police scandals, including the murder of a man in custody. On the contrary, I'm disappointed by the lack of consequences for the officers involved. But I voted for Ashcraft once, and I'll do it again.</p>
<p>By contrast, her opponent Trish Spencer is a trash fire of a candidate. Spencer was the incumbent ousted by Ashcraft, and her time as mayor was chaos. Multiple scandals. Alameda-sized scandals, but still. Council meetings ran long. Police quit in droves. People in city hall found her difficult.</p>
<p>Spencer's been on the city council since losing the mayoral race, and her time on the city council has been characterized by obstruction and NIMBYism. I am relieved that I do not have to vote for Trish to protect my home.</p>
<p>Vote yes on Ashcraft. But just as important, vote no on Spencer.</p>
<h1>City of Alameda City Council</h1>
<p><strong>Hannah Groce &amp; Paul Beusterien. </strong>The Alameda City Council race is crowded this year, with six candidates vying for two open positions. The election determines whether we'll have a progressive vs. moderate majority in the city council. The progressives will continue to push alternatives to cars in our transit plan and favor renter protections. Moderates will go hard to reverse existing tenant protections, oppose building more housing, and will likely continue the typical California NIMBY tactics to slow growth.</p>
<p>I favor Hannah Groce (progressive) and Paul Beusterien (moderate). Tracy Jensen is also a great candidate and my alternate to Paul B.</p>
<p>It seems like I don't need to explain my choice for Hannah Groce very much. She's got the progressive bona fides; she'll do great.</p>
<p>I favor Paul Beusterien for two reasons. First, we don't have anyone representing my neighborhood on the city council, and Paul's from Bay Farm. More than that, he serves on the master HOA board that covers nearly 4000 households and does so well. If you'd like to check for yourself, his voting record as part of that HOA board is an open record. I think he's ready to level up to full city council.</p>
<p>But that's not enough to get me behind him entirely in a race that has this many candidates. What pushes me over the line is that I am confident that Paul will be on my side in the fight against the redevelopment of the Harbor Bay Club site. Paul actually came to our neighborhood, talked with us about the issue, and listened. No other candidate has done so.<br><br>Paul generally favors solutions that protect the tennis club site as commercial recreation and wants to find ways to restore it to vibrancy. I prefer non-commercial solutions myself, but this is close enough. He has my vote.</p>
<h1>Measure 1 (legal abortion)</h1>
<p><strong><span data-preserver-spaces="true">Hell yes. </span></strong><span data-preserver-spaces="true">This measure will enshrine the right to abortion, birth control, and the right to refuse birth control into the state constitution. With forced birth now the law of the land in half of the United States, the country needs California to lead here. It's a no-brainer.</span></p>
<h1>Measure 26 (expand tribal casinos)</h1>
<p><span data-preserver-spaces="true"><strong>I guess yes.</strong> I dislike gambling; I've seen it ruin too many lives. But I favor tribal sovereignty and dislike prohibitions. So I'll hold my nose and vote yes.</span></p>
<h1>Measure 27 (online sports betting)</h1>
<p><span data-preserver-spaces="true"><strong>No. </strong>Another gambling proposition. Again, I dislike prohibitions, but Measure 28 is designed as a corporate end-run around the California state legislature, who could pass laws legalizing this type of betting if they wanted to. They don't want to, so well-funded predators are trying to capture business from the tribal casinos via ballot initiative. Fuck these people.</span></p>
<h1>Measure 28 (arts in schools)</h1>
<p><strong>Hell yes. </strong>It sucks that we have to do all this dancing around Prop 13 to get our schools funded, but that's life. Every kid in California should have the opportunity to make art, and underfunded schools deserve arts programs.</p>
<h1>Measure 29 (Dialysis Clinics Again)</h1>
<p><strong><span data-preserver-spaces="true">Yes. </span></strong><span data-preserver-spaces="true">Unions have been trying to protect the workers in California dialysis clinics for a long time, and powerful medical lobbies have effectively shut them out. The unions have put worker protections on the ballot in the last few elections, and every time they get outspent ten to one and lose. The clinics claim all their patients will die because they'll all close down if they had to treat their workers like human beings.</span></p>
<p><span data-preserver-spaces="true">The unions are trying again this year, and the (wildly profitable) dialysis clinic companies are trotting out ads featuring old ladies begging us not to murder them. It's sick.</span></p>
<p><span data-preserver-spaces="true">I doubt any clinics will close if this passes, but it won't. I'm pro-union, so I'm voting yes anyway.</span></p>
<h1>Measure 30 (Tax the rich to fund electric cars)</h1>
<p><strong><span data-preserver-spaces="true">Yes. </span></strong><span data-preserver-spaces="true">So Lyft will save some money, so fucking what? We're in a climate emergency, and the rich don't have to pay federal income taxes. Make their accountants earn those fees by dancing around this tax too. The worst case scenario here, if it passes, is that we get more electric cars, and billionaires don't buy their way out of future taxes at the ballot. Tax the rich! What's controversial about that?</span></p>
<h1>Measure 31 (Keep law banning flavored tobacco)</h1>
<p><strong>Soft yes.</strong> Measure 31 is a big company trying to buy a veto around the state legislature via a ballot initiative. Again, I don't like prohibitions, but I dislike big corporations trying to buy their way past the state legislature even more. Fight it in the state house, not at the ballot initiative, and support representative democracy.</p>
<h2 id="alameda-county-d-more-buildings-on-agricultural-land-yes">Alameda County D (buildings on agricultural land)</h2>
<p><strong><span data-preserver-spaces="true">Yes. </span></strong><span data-preserver-spaces="true">This one is deep policy wonk stuff. Alameda County prohibits building on many agricultural lands; this allows limited development for equestrian and agricultural buildings. The county supervisors proposed and support it, and the Sierra Club has no opinion, so I will trust the supervisors to do their jobs.</span></p>
<h1>City of Alameda E (City council pay increases)</h1>
<p><strong><span data-preserver-spaces="true">Hell Yes. </span></strong><span data-preserver-spaces="true">Serving in elected city leadership in Alameda pays jack shit. City council members make $1200 a year, and the mayor makes $3600 a year. True, city leadership is a part-time job in a city structured in a weak-mayor, strong-city-manager way, but those numbers are too low. We're asking our elected officials to work for free, which cuts everyone out of the candidate pool who can't afford to do that.</span></p>
<p><span data-preserver-spaces="true">If this passes, the city council's pay will jump to $25,000 in 2023. Future pay increases would be based on a formula not to exceed 30 percent of the median Bay Area annual salary, which is... weird? But not unreasonable. They haven't had a raise since the 1970s; we should do it.</span></p>
<p><span data-preserver-spaces="true">If you want professionals in the job, pay them like professionals.</span></p>
<h1>City of Alameda F (Hotel taxes)</h1>
<p><strong><span data-preserver-spaces="true">Yes. </span></strong><span data-preserver-spaces="true">This increases the hotel tax to 14%, in line with other cities in the area. It sucks because it's a direct voting tax, not something the city council can set itself. But that's life in California for you. But I don't see a downside beyond entrenching our existing government dysfunction.</span></p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
</feed>
